<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Computing Assignments</title><link>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Computing Assignments</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Depth of Field</title><link>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/depth-of-field/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/depth-of-field/</guid><description>Depth of field # Introduction # This effect describes the distance between the nearest and farthest objects in a scene that appear acceptably sharp in an image. The depth of field is affected by the focal length of the lens, the aperture of the lens, and the distance between the subject and the camera.
Antecedents # The depth of field is affected by the focal length of the lens, the aperture of the lens, the distance between the subject and the camera, and the acceptable circle of confusion.</description></item><item><title>2. Linear Perspective</title><link>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/linear-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/linear-perspective/</guid><description>Linear perspective # Introduction # Linear perspective is a visual illusion which objective is to create an illusion of depth on a flat surface. All parallel lines (orthogonals) in a painting or drawing using this system converge in a single vanishing point on the composition’s horizon line.
Leonardo da Vinci&amp;rsquo;s Adoration of the Magi, one of the earliest depictions of linear perspective # Antecedents and previous work # From Encyclopedia Britannica Source # Origin of linear perspective</description></item><item><title>3. Parallax</title><link>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/parallax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/parallax/</guid><description>Parallax # Parallax is one of the foundations of spatial perception, by moving our point of view changes the relative position of observable objects.
We perceive this every day, but it is a feature that is not taken into account because it is very familiar to our eyes, my example of approach is for example the transmilenio that goes along Avenida 30, in which through the window we can see the hills of Bogota in the distance, moving in a relatively slow way, with respect to how it is moving the facades of houses, buildings and other structures near this avenue.</description></item><item><title>4. A joint example of depth perception</title><link>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/joint-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.github.io/visual-computing-assignments/docs/visual-illusions/joint-example/</guid><description>Joint example of depth perception # Introduction # In this example we aim for a combined representation of the three visual illusions presented previously. Used correctly, the union of techniques of depth of field, linear perspective and parallax can lead to a very convincing 2D representation of a 3D space.
Antecedents and previous work # The examples and theoretical development of each of the techniques used
Depth of field Linear perspective Parallax Solution - a p5.</description></item></channel></rss>