<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Computing Assignments</title><link>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Computing Assignments</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Lights</title><link>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/light/</guid><description>Lights # Introduction # With our code, you can delve into the world of computer-generated visuals and explore different types of lights to achieve stunning visual effects in your projects. You have the flexibility to switch between three main light types: &amp;ldquo;Point Light&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Directional Light&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Ambient Light&amp;rdquo;. Each light type offers a distinct way to illuminate and accentuate objects in your scene.
A standout feature of our code is the ability to precisely control the position of the light source.</description></item><item><title>2. Rendering by raycasting</title><link>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/raycast-rendering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/raycast-rendering/</guid><description>Raycasting # Introduction # Raycasting is a technique used in computer graphics and game development to simulate the behavior of rays of light. It involves tracing rays from a specific origin in a scene and determining the objects or surfaces they intersect with. Raycasting is widely used for various purposes, such as rendering &amp;ldquo;3D&amp;rdquo; graphics, implementing collision detection, and creating visual effects like reflections and shadows.
This method of 3D scene rendering is what made Wolfenstein 3D a technichal achievement fir graphics of its time.</description></item><item><title>3. Post Effects</title><link>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/post-effects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mondracode.com/visual-computing-assignments/docs/rendering-and-space-transformation/post-effects/</guid><description>Introduction # For post effects we show the depth of field using WebGL shaders. The depth of field is a post effect that simulates the focus of a camera. The focus is set to the center of the screen and the depth of field is calculated using the distance of the objects to the camera. This effect is achieved in P5.js using a shader that blurs the objects in the scene.</description></item></channel></rss>